Inventory of the Gvido Augusts collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Gvido Augusts collection
1940-1972.
73027
Augusts, Gvido, collector.
1 folder, 18 motion picture film reels (2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Latvian motion picture film, including dramas, documentaries, and newsreels, depicting daily life in Latvia, various aspects of Latvian culture, and postwar treatment of events in Latvia during World War II; and orders, certificates, and miscellany, relating to conditions in Latvia during and after World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1973.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Contains Latvian motion picture film, including dramas, documentaries, and newsreels, depicting daily life in Latvia, various aspects of Latvian culture, and postwar treatment of events in Latvia during World War II; and orders, certificates, and miscellany, relating to conditions in Latvia during and after World War II. Film titles taken directly from the canister or reel.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
World War, 1939-1945--Latvia.; Latvia--Social conditions.; Motion pictures.
Collection Contents
- Orders, certificates, and miscellany relating to conditions in Latvia during and after World War II (Folder 10.V)
- Film reels, 1953-1972 (Film shelf Film shelf)
  For information on getting a use copy, please contact Hoover Institution Archives
  - "Rita," 16mm, 2 reels, 1957
    A black and white feature film directed by Ada Neretniece about a young girl named Rita who helps escaped and wounded war prisoners in German occupoied Latvia between 1943-1944 until they are liberated by the Red Army. Film is a propoganda film that documents the attitudes of the Communist regime during that period in Latvian history. Produced in 1957, the film is 1.5 hours long.
  - "Diena bez Vakara #4, Diena bez Vakara #2," 16mm, 2 reels, 1962
    The full length feature film directed by Maris Rudzitis in 1962 is a social drama set in early 1960s in Latvia, depicting a doctor's well-to-do family. The film is 1.5 hours long.
  - "Ta Pati Zeme," 16mm, 1970
    Commissioned by the Latvian SSR Ministry for Agriculture in 1970, The film depicts life on a dairy farm near Valmiera and shows close-ups of people at work and play. The film is 18 minutes long.
  - #203 Newsreels, Cultural newsreels from, 1962
  - Hit Parade 1960, 930 feet, 16mm
  - "Andrejs Upttis (1953) Kalnrre (1972), Kulturkronika (66)," 16mm, 2 reels
  - "Salina Pavasart I (Rigs 1956) Kultin chronikes (1962) 2, 3, 4, Salina Pavasart II (Rigs 1956), Salina Pav #202," 16mm, 3 reels
  - Song Festival - RIGA TV, 1150 feet, 16mm, 1965
  - "Fishing on the Baltic," 700 feet, 16mm, 1955
  - Two short films made by amateur film makers in Soviet Latvia, aprox. 900ft., Black/White, Magnetic sound, 900 feet, 16mm, 1971-1972
  - Unidentified reels, undated
    Among several of the unidentified films, the collection may possibly include 'Maija Svetki Riga 1960', a student film; 'Salna Pavasari', a full-length feature film depicting a tragic love story in 19th century Latvia, as well as other films and newsreels related to Latvia.